Philip Joubert

I am a 30-year-old bilingual male. I have a team-based personality; I foreground a positive attitude, I am reliable, I work well under pressure, and I am an adaptable individual who enjoys new challenges. I enjoy writing and reading; in particular, I am very passionate about English Literature.

South Africa

Empangeni, KZN

ppjoub107@gmail.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/de veloper-phil/ https://github.com/Mr-Fennie

EXPERIENCE

Bouldergram Project, Remote — Web Development

April 2021 - PRESENT

I am currently working on the front and back end development of Bouldergram, a prototype social media site that focuses on rock climbing. Working on this project has provided me with the opportunity to hone my skills in html5, CSS3, JavaScript, Python and use Django as a framework.

Freelance, Remote — *Photographer/Filmographer*

July 2013 - PRESENT

In my spare time, I do freelance work in creative pursuits that range from filming, photographing, editing and directing. Most notably, I have co-directed and filmed the 'Lo Mama' music video for a South African musician named Alta and assisted with creating media content for Badger Skateboards.

Felixton College, Felixton — *Teaching Assistant*

July 2015 - December 2020

I started working as a Teaching Intern at Felixton College and progressed to Teaching Assistant. My duties included; teaching and assisting in Life Orientation, English, Drama and History, coaching seasonal sports (Hockey, Soccer, Basketball), leading a music band and photography culture club program, assisting with the school marimba band, facilitate and teach skateboarding on an annual school camp and lead groups on an annual multi-day hike on the Giant's Cup Trail.

JS Gericke Library, Stellenbosch — *Student Assistant*

January 2013 - December 2014

I was a student assistant at the University of Stellenbosch's Library. My duties included working at the circulation desk, issuing and returning client's books, receiving clients book fines, searching for lost books and organizing, reshelving and maintaining the short loan section, which included sections for DVD's, specialised Law books and specialised books for every subject. My duties also included reserving special books for clients and issuing interlibrary loan books and academic articles.

SKILLS

MS Office suite, Google Workspace.

Html, CSS, Javascript, Python, Django.

Adobe Premiere Pro, Adobe Lightroom, Adobe Audition.

Guitar, Bass, Trombone, Trumpet, Piano, Vocals.

INTERESTS

Reading - History, Fiction, Philosophy, autobiographies.

Physical Exercise - Rock climbing, running, cycling, hiking, yoga, squash, skateboarding and kayaking

Culinary Art - Cooking from different cultures and baking.

Construction - Woodwork and Concrete. I built my own climbing wall, volumes, various kitchen tools and assisted in building the flat I live in.

Music - I enjoy making my own music whether it be on my own or as part of a group.

Rust en Vrede, Stellenbosch — Waiter

September 2013 - December 2014

I worked at Rust en Vrede during the Summer Season as a waiter and occasional Barman. Rust en Vrede is a fine dining restaurant that regularly ranks in the top 5 restaurants in South Africa.

Lancet Laboratories, Empangeni — *Admin Staff*

March 2009 - December 2009

I worked for Lancet Laboratories in Empangeni during my gap year in 2009. I held an administrative title but was responsible for fetching, receiving and shipping important blood and pathology specimens, working with and assisting patients, printing and delivering crucial patient test results to doctors and making sure that the hospital was stocked up with Lancet specimen containers.

Protea Hotel- The Richards, Richard's Bay — *Musician*

January 2008 - September 2008

I worked as a live musician in the hotel bar on Ladies Night, every Wednesday for close to a year. My duties included playing a 4-hour setlist on guitar or bass, as well as taking requests from the crowd.

EDUCATION

Udemy, Online — Full-Stack Web Development Bootcamp

March 2021 - May 2021

I completed a Python & Django Full-Stack web development bootcamp online. For the course, I had to learn and build small projects with HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Python and Django.

I-to-i TEFL, Online — TEFL Certificate - 180 hours

February 2021 - March 2021

I completed a level 5, 180 hour TEFL certificate online. For the course, I had to submit three individual lesson plans and complete a test on each module before moving on to the next.

Stellenbosch University, Stellenbosch — Ba Language and Culture

January 2010 - December 2014 (Incomplete)

I started, but did not complete, a Ba Degree in Language and Culture at the University of Stellenbosch, with English, Applied English Studies, Visual Studies, Philosophy, Theatre Studies and basic Xhosa. I passed all modules excluding the two required to graduate.

Empangeni High School, Empangeni — National Senior Certificate

January 2004 - December 2008

I completed Matric at Empangeni High School. My subjects were Afrikaans, English, Mathematical Literacy, Music, Business Economics and Biology.

LANGUAGES

English and Afrikaans.